When talking about multidimensional array, we are not talking about only two dimensional array exclusively,
so we can make 2D array for a for the array five and so on.
But when a multidimensional array is an array of arrays that can hold more than one row and column three
dimensional arrays are not commonly used in real time application.
Therefore, two dimensional arrays are given more preferences in programming examples.
OK.
So this is a 3D array.
The 3D dimensional array and I told you, in order to detect the number of dimensions or to specify
the number of dimensions of your array, this is indicated by the number of angle brackets pairs.
OK.
When you declare so, we have arranged two.
Here we are created new and nine nine nine row column depth.
This and or hide this is a 3D Rubik's Cube.
You can think about it, or you can think about it like a list of arrays.
It's sometimes and that and may be usually different to imagine how a 3D array works, but it is the
like.
This example is most specified and most like simplified the index.
The first array at Index zero is contained in a two dimensional array starting from 11 12, 13, 14,
15, 16, 17, 18 and 19.
This is the first array.
This is at index zero.
So the first I the the the first index, I would be at zero.
So.
Let me show you this is.
This is here and think about it.
It is of index zero.
So we are talking about index zero.
This is that.
Now let's move to index one.
So Index one would be contained in the the second at two the array, which starts by 21, 22, 23,
24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29.
OK.
This is how we think about it through the array and how to create this city.
And the last one to second, that third, fourth and so on.
OK, now how to print a 3-D out of there in order to print a 3-D array?
I told you when making.
And one making 3-D array or 2D array or one single array.
We used loops.
But this depends how many loops we are going to nest if we are walking.
And through the elements of two the array, I should make a nested loop of two loops.
OK.
If we are going to print a 3-D array, I should make a three nested loops because one for the element
and the one for the arrays sheets.
The second is for the columns and the rows and the third for the columns and so on.
If I make for the array, I need four nested loops.
OK.
When a number of dimensions of the array increase that complexity of imagination, instantiation and
adding the values and storing the variables inside it would be more and more complex.
So add this example we have this array.
I need to create a for loop that starts from zero to less than two because we have three sheets.
So and the zero, one and two.
Zero one two is equal to two, it should be equal to two.
So I have fixed I equal to three now.
This is for the number of sheets because we have one sheet.
Do second, second and 3:30.
We start from zero, one and two now, Jay is the number of zeros in each sheet.
So we have this is the first row, the second row and the third is this sorry, the first row, second
row and third row.
We represented the first row by index zero, one and two.
OK.
The number four here.
No, AK is less than four represent the number of columns of this array.
And again, there is an error.
I have missed this because I have worked on an example before this.
So OK is less than three and not not less than four.
It starts from zero.
One and two.
These are these are the calm, so that way, how to print it.
We start by selecting the cheat going into roll and the column and print that element.
So for that, we have a of I, J and J.
This is the way to print the number of the cheat.
That says, if we need to print number 17.
So if I need to print this, this is at the first sheet.
So I put here.
I of zero.
If I need to access sorry, if I need to access this element and print it, I don't need to use the
four nested loops.
I'm specifying directly that a number of the array and the number of the elements inside this Saturday.
But if I need to print, all the elements are used in nested loop.
No, I try.
I'm going to try to print the element and find this element.
So 17, I need to get the value at this corner.
It is on the first sheet, so I put zero here.
At the index, I, the Index J is equal to the index of the row, so it is one zero one and two, so
it is on the second.
Index Arrow or in the third row, OK, third row is index equal to do it is on the first column, so
it is on zero.
OK, OK.
If I put system that out, the print a at index zero two zero, it will give me 70.
This is how we work with three the array and how to access elements and how to print a 3-D array.
And it's very simple.
It's similar to to the array and the single dimensional array.
But it made with my was more complexity because we're working through 3D array.
We are going to a three dimensional array and sheet in rows and in columns, so I need to search using
a complexity of all and cube.
OK.
So when we print a 3D array or we search for an element in its 3D array, we are working with time complexity
of.